now that we have seen how instruction
scheduling works let's see how it
interacts with things like if conversion
recall that if conversion works like
this we had some code and then there is
an if then else which means there is a
branch
sometimes we do this sometimes we do
this and then we go back to doing
something after the if then else
let's say this is the orange code and
let's say that this is the green code
before if conversion we can easily
reschedule code within here
we can also move things around within
this we can move things around within
this and we can move things around
within this but it's hard to mix the
code from these together for example
take an instruction from here to fill a
stall here because if we end up going
this way that instruction doesn't get
done so it gets a lot more complicated
however after if conversion we do the
stuff that was before the if then else
we then have the orange code predicated
so that it only results in execution
and then we have the orange code
predicated one way
green's a code predicated the other way
and then the stuff after the loop and
now because this is branch-free code
and because all of these instructions
really execute every time it's just that
they're predicated sometimes
we can easily take instructions from
here and put them here to avoid stalls
and that's nice we can even take
instructions from here and put them here
or instructions from here and put them
here for that matter we can even take
instructions from here and put them here
so overall we get a lot more
opportunities for filling stall cycles
with something useful so if conversion
is one of those things that it helps
with branch prediction because you avoid
branches
and it also can tremendously help the
compiler in making a better schedule for
a processor